rackroomshoes.com 2017-04-16

# Rack Room Shoes | Shoes, Boots, Sneakers, Sandals

## Privacy Policy

**This Privacy Policy (the “Policy”) is intended to explain what Rack Room Shoes does with your information and what you can expect from Rack Room Shoes regarding the privacy of your information, including:**

  1. Information We Collect  
 
  2. Cookies  
 
  3. How We Use Information  
 
  4. How We Share Information  
 
  5. Contests and Sweepstakes  
 
  6. Opt Out Policy  
 
  7. Policy Changes  
 
  8. California Privacy Rights  
 
  9. Children's Policy  

1.  **Information We Collect**  
Rack Room Shoes may collect certain personally identifiable information that is voluntarily provided by you, such as your name, address, e-mail address, phone number and, in regard to online purchases only, your credit card number. We collect such information when you purchase items online, sign up for the Rack Room Shoes Rewards program, email updates or participate in one of our contests, sweepstakes or online promotions (as applicable). We may also collect information concerning gift recipients in order to fulfill gift orders. Rack Room Shoes does not collect any personally identifiable information through cookies or beacons. If you have submitted personally identifiable information and would like to change that information, please log in to your Rack Room Shoes Rewards program account and edit your information. If you are not a member of the Rewards program, you can follow the instructions in the "Opt Out Policy" section below to stop receiving e-mail and/or text communications from Rack Room Shoes.

2.  **Cookies**  
A cookie is a piece of data stored on the hard drive of your computer, containing information about you. Usage of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on our site. Cookies can make the browsing experience easier. For instance, by accepting a cookie from our site, we can provide you a more personalized experience while shopping, thereby saving time while on our site. Most browsers can be set to reject cookies or to ask you if you want to accept/reject an incoming cookie. If you reject the cookie, you may still use our site, although you will be limited in some areas of our site. Cookies can also enable us to track and target the interests of our customers to enhance the experience on our site.

3.  **How We Use Information**  
When you purchase items from the Rack Room Shoes website, we will use your information to process the order, as well as to contact you if we have any questions or concerns about your order and to provide shipping confirmation.

If you “opt in” for e-mail or text communications from Rack Room Shoes, we may provide you with promotional information coupons, or offers at the contact information that you have provided.

At no time are you obligated to provide us with any personal information in order to use and enjoy our website. It is Rack Room Shoes’ policy to collect only that information that Rack Room Shoes needs to meet our customers' needs, conduct our business efficiently, and communicate special or specific offers to you. There is no consequence if you do not wish to provide Rack Room Shoes with your personally identifiable information, except that you will not receive certain communications that are delivered only to our opt in list and, you will not be able to purchase items on our website without providing your name, address, e-mail address and phone number.

If you agree to receive mobile text coupons or other mobile text communications from Rack Room Shoes, you agree that Rack Room Shoes may send any information, including promotional or marketing text messages, via text message to the phone number you provided. You are not required to consent to receive text messages in order to make a purchase from Rack Room Shoes in the future. If you want to stop receiving text communications from Rack Room Shoes, please see the “Opt Out Policy” section below for instructions on how to opt out. 

4. **How We Share Information**  
In connection with the uses outlined in this Policy only, Rack Room Shoes may share your information with our website hosting partners and may use certain third-party marketing services firms as necessary to deliver e-mail communications or online ads to those on our opt-in list. We do not sell any personally identifiable information concerning our users. We may also release your personal information to comply with the law or to protect our or others' rights, property, or safety. As with any business, it is possible that as our business develops, we may sell or buy online stores or other assets. In such transactions, information concerning customers often is among the transferred assets. Accordingly, in the unlikely event that our company or substantially all of our assets are acquired by a third party, such information may be one of the transferred assets. Rack Room Shoes values the privacy of its customers and visitors to this website. Therefore, Rack Room Shoes endeavors to comply with relevant ethical standards in gathering, using and safeguarding customer information that is entrusted to Rack Room Shoes. Please note that, despite our diligence, new technology is constantly evolving and Rack Room Shoes cannot immediately implement all new technology upon development.

If you feel at any time that your personally identifiable information has been compromised by Rack Room Shoes, please contact us immediately at [customercare@rackroom.com](mailto:customercare@rackroom.com). 

5.  **Contests and Sweepstakes**  
If you participate in one of our online contests or sweepstakes, we may use your information to further update you on the promotion in which you participated. If you “opt in” for communications from Rack Room Shoes, we will use the contact information you provided to send you promotional information, coupons or other communications. Online purchasers and participants in contests, sweepstakes and promotions may also be included on our “opt in” list. If you submit any or post one or more text comments (such as user reviews), photographs (“User Content") on the Rack Room Web Site we do not guarantee any confidentiality. However, we will not share any User Content with any third parties except as set forth above or in accordance with the Terms of Use.

6.  **Opt Out Policy**  
If at any time you no longer wish to receive communications from us, you are free to “opt out” of receiving these communications.

a) **E-mail Communications**. If you would no longer like to receive e-mailed coupons, special events information, sales notifications or other messages from Rack Room Shoes, please click and follow the “Unsubscribe” instructions in your e-mail. Your e-mail address and other personal information will be removed from our marketing list. OPTING OUT OF RECEIVING E-MAILS WILL ONLY AFFECT YOUR RECEIPT OF E-MAILS. YOU MAY STILL RECEIVE MESSAGES FROM RACK ROOM SHOES VIA TEXT MESSAGE OR OTHER METHODS.

b) **Text Messages**. If you wish to opt out of receiving text messages, or if you have errantly received a marketing text message without opting in to the program, you can cancel the program at any time by texting STOP RRS to 77550. OPTING OUT OF RECEIVING TEXT MESSAGES WILL ONLY AFFECT YOUR RECEIPT OF TEXT MESSAGES. YOU MAY STILL RECEIVE MESSAGES FROM RACK ROOM SHOES VIA E-MAIL OR OTHER METHODS. You may text HELP RRS to 77550 to receive additional information regarding Rack Room Shoes’ Mobile Alerts Program. STANDARD MESSAGE AND DATA RATES MAY APPLY. WHILE RACK ROOM SHOES DOES NOT CHARGE ANY FEE FOR USING ITS SERVICE, YOUR USE OF THE SERVICE VIA TEXT, MULTIMEDIA, OR INSTANT MESSAGE ON YOUR MOBILE PHONE OR ANY OTHER DEVICE IS SUBJECT TO THE STANDARD MESSAGE AND DATA CHARGES PER YOUR CARRIER’S RATE PLAN.

7.  **Policy Changes**  
Rack Room Shoes reserves the right to change our Policy as our business changes. If this Policy changes, we will post an updated Policy on our website. You can tell if this Policy has changed by checking the revision date and version number that appear at the end of this Policy.

To assist you in acquiring additional information, the Rack Room Shoes site may have links to websites operated by third parties. Those websites will have their own policies on privacy that you may wish to review. Rack Room Shoes has no responsibility concerning the content or operation of these linked websites.

8.  **California Privacy Rights**  
Under California’s “Shine the Light” law, California residents who provide personal information in obtaining products or services for personal, family, or household use are entitled to request and obtain from us once a calendar year information about the customer information we shared, if any, with other businesses for their own direct marketing uses. If applicable, this information would include the categories of customer information and the names and addresses of those businesses with which we shared customer information for the immediately prior calendar year.

9.  **Children’s Policy**  
Rack Room Shoes is dedicated to protecting the privacy of all of its customers, especially children under the age of 13. Additionally, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (“COPPA”) requires that we inform parents and legal guardians about how we collect, use, and disclose personally identifiable information from children under the age of 13. COPPA also requires that we obtain the consent of parents and guardians in order for children under the age of 13 to provide certain information to us.

The following is an explanation of our policies regarding collection of information from children under the age of 13. The term “child” or “children” below refers to such children under the age of 13 and the term “parent” below includes legal guardians. 

(a) **Collection of Information**. In connection with certain online sweepstakes and promotions only, Rack Room Shoes may knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children. In such event, the information collected will be limited to the child’s name, age, address, e-mail address and the e-mail address of his or her parent. Pursuant to applicable laws, Rack Room Shoes will not condition a child's participation in any online activity on the child providing more personally identifiable information than is reasonably necessary. All information will be collected by the active submission of such information by the child, and not through the use of cookies or beacons. 

(b) **Use of the Information and Disclosure to Third Parties**. If a child registers for a sweepstakes or other promotion, we use the parent’s e-mail address to notify the parent of the child’s registration request (see below). All other personally identifiable information collected from the child will be used for the express purpose of operating the sweepstakes or promotion only, which may include notification to the child regarding rules and results of the sweepstakes and/or e-mail messages to the child regarding in-store or online promotions. In connection with such use only, we may share the child's personally identifiable information with our website hosting partners and certain third-party marketing services firms, as necessary. These parties have agreed to maintain the privacy and security of the personally identifiable information. In addition, we may share a child’s personally identifiable information with third parties to the extent reasonably necessary to: protect the security of integrity of our sites; to take precautions against liability; to respond to judicial process; or to the extent permitted under provisions of law, to provide information to law enforcement agencies or for an investigation related to public safety. Except for the limited disclosures described in this paragraph, we will not make any public disclosure (on our website or a chat page, for example) of any personally identifiable information provided to us by a child. As provided in the “How We Use Information” and “How We Share Information” sections above, we do not sell any personally identifiable information concerning our users. 

(c) **Parental Consent.** If Rack Room Shoes has actual knowledge that any child under the age of 13 has attempted to provide any personally identifiable information, we will send an e-mail to the parental e-mail address provided to us, and allow the parent to verify the child’s submission (and our subsequent collection and use for a stated purpose) of personally identifiable information. If the parent does not consent to allow the child's submission (and our subsequent collection and use for a stated purpose), we will promptly delete the child's information from our database. If for any reason, the e-mail sent to the parental e-mail address is undeliverable, we will delete the child’s submission as if the parent refused the child’s submission. In the event a child wins a sweepstakes or contest, and we want to publicize the name (and/or other personally identifiable information) of such child, we will again notify the parent at the parent's e-mail address and request that the parent provide his or her name and address for delivery of the applicable release and consent form. We will not publish or release the name or other personally identifiable information of any child as a winner of any contest without the express written consent of the child's parent. 

(d) **Review and Deletion of Information**. A parent can contact our customer service department at any time to review, change, or delete the personally identifiable information that we have collected from his or her child. A parent may also expressly request that a child's information not be shared with those limited third-parties with which we may share information, as necessary (and except as may be required pursuant to applicable laws), pursuant to (b) above. If you need any further information, or have any questions regarding our collection of personally identifiable information, please contact us at [customercare@rackroom.com](mailto:customercare@rackroom.co).

This Privacy Policy was last updated on 01/21/2016 and is Version 3.0
